const arr = [{"id":0,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"Which of the following conditions is characterized by a spike and dome appearance of the glomerular basement membrane on electron microscopy?","answers":[{"option":"Membranoproliferative glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Post-streptococcal glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Minimal change disease","bool":false},{"option":"Rapidly progressive glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous glomerulonephritis","bool":true}]},{"id":1,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A dead body of a girl was brought for autopsy. On examination, she was pregnant, and severe injuries were observed in her pelvic area. On inquiry, her mother told that she tried to criminally induce abortion during which she died within minutes. What is the most probable cause of death?","answers":[{"option":"Secondary hemorrhage","bool":false},{"option":"Peritonitis","bool":false},{"option":"Vagal inhibition","bool":true},{"option":"Renal Failure","bool":false},{"option":"Septicemia","bool":false}]},{"id":2,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"Anatomical waste should be disposed off in which color-coded bag?","answers":[{"option":"Yellow","bool":true},{"option":"Red","bool":false},{"option":"White","bool":false},{"option":"Black","bool":false},{"option":"Blue","bool":false}]},{"id":3,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 30-year-old unmarried woman came to a doctor and requested her to induce an abortion. The doctor refused and told the women there is severe punishment for criminal abortion in Pakistan. What is the punishment of criminal abortion before babies' organs are formed in Pakistan?","answers":[{"option":"Full diyat of the child","bool":false},{"option":"3 years imprisonment if with consent","bool":true},{"option":"1/20 diyat of the child","bool":false},{"option":"7 years imprisonment","bool":false},{"option":"3 years imprisonment if without consent","bool":false}]},{"id":4,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"In Pakistan, on which grounds is abortion justifiable?","answers":[{"option":"Humanitarian grounds","bool":false},{"option":"Eugenic grounds","bool":false},{"option":"Therapeutic grounds","bool":true},{"option":"Threatened","bool":false},{"option":"Social grounds","bool":false}]},{"id":5,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A graduate student is planning to make a high-altitude climb in South America while on vacation. He will not have time to acclimate slowly to the altitude. What drug is useful in preventing high-altitude sickness?","answers":[{"option":"Acetazolamide","bool":true},{"option":"Desmopressin","bool":false},{"option":"Amiloride","bool":false},{"option":"Demeclocycline","bool":false},{"option":"Ethacrynic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":6,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 60-year-old patient has a clinical history of frequent episodes of renal colic with calcium-containing stones. His clinical workup indicates that he has a defect in proximal tubular calcium reabsorption. Which of the following diuretic agent is most useful in the treatment of recurrent calcium stones?","answers":[{"option":"Spironolactone","bool":false},{"option":"Mannitol","bool":false},{"option":"Diazoxide","bool":false},{"option":"Chlorthalidone","bool":true},{"option":"Ethacrynic acid","bool":false}]},{"id":7,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 60-year-old man seeks medical attention because of recurrent urinary tract\r\ninfections. The patient has a history of increasing difficulty in\r\nurination, decreased flow, straining, and hesitancy over the last several\r\nmonths. Prostate-specific antigen (PSA) level is mildly elevated and a\r\nprostate biopsy proves benign. Which of the following is the most appropriate\r\ninitial management of this patient with benign prostatic hyperplasia (BPH)?","answers":[{"option":"Transurethral resection of the prostate (TURP)","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha adrenergic blocker","bool":true},{"option":"5-Alpha reductase inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha adrenergic blocker and 5-alpha reductase inhibitor","bool":false},{"option":"Open prostatectomy","bool":false}]},{"id":8,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 55-year-old man presents with fever and pain in the perineal region. Upon\r\nfurther questioning, he also complains of frequency, urgency, dysuria, and a\r\ndecreased urinary stream. On physical examination his abdomen Is soft, non-distended, and non-tender, Digital  Rectal examination (DRE) demonstrates exquisite\r\ntenderness on the anterior aspect. Laboratory investigation reveals\r\nleukocytosis and findings on urinalysis are consistent with a bacterial\r\ninfection. Which of the following is the most likely diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Pyelonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Prostatitis","bool":true},{"option":"Benign prostatic hyperplasia","bool":false},{"option":"Nephrolithiasis","bool":false},{"option":"Urinary tract infection","bool":false}]},{"id":9,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 36-year-old man presents to the emergency room with renal colic. His vital\r\nsigns are normal and a urinalysis shows microscopic hematuria. A radiograph\r\nreveals a 1.6 cm stone. Which of the following Is the most appropriate\r\nmanagement of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Percutancous nephrostomy tube","bool":false},{"option":"Hydration and analgesics","bool":false},{"option":"Open surgery to remove the stone","bool":false},{"option":"Alpha adrenergic blocker","bool":false},{"option":"Extracorporeal lithotripsy","bool":true}]},{"id":10,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 32-year-old man presents with an asymptomatic mass in his right testicle. On examination, the mass cannot be transilluminated. Ultrasound shows a solid mass in the right testicle. Which of the following is the most accurate method in obtaining a diagnosis of testicular cancer?","answers":[{"option":"Percutaneous biopsy of testicular mass","bool":false},{"option":"Excisional biopsy of the testicular mass with scrotal incision","bool":false},{"option":"Serum level of alpha-fetoprotein and beta human chorionic gonadotropin","bool":false},{"option":"Radical inguinal orchidectomy","bool":true},{"option":"Incisional biopsy of testicular mass through a scrotal incision","bool":false}]},{"id":11,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 10-year-old boy presents to the emergency room with pain In the left testicle. The pain is acute in onset and began 1 hour ago. On physical examination, he has a  high riding, firm, and markedly tender left testis. The right testicle is normal. Urinalysis is unremarkable. Which of the following is the most appropriate management of this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Manual detorsion of the left testicle with internal rotation towards the thigh, orchidopexy if the condition recurs","bool":false},{"option":"Orchidopexy of bilateral testicles","bool":false},{"option":"Orchidopexy of the left testicle","bool":false},{"option":"Orchiectomy of the left testicle","bool":false},{"option":"Manual detorsion of the left testicle with external rotation towards the thigh, orchidopexy if the condition recurs","bool":true}]},{"id":12,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"Which one of the following statistical tests Is appropriate for normally distributed continuous data?","answers":[{"option":"McNemar’s test","bool":false},{"option":"Wilcoxon test","bool":false},{"option":"Chi-square test","bool":false},{"option":"Levene’s test","bool":false},{"option":"Student’s t- test","bool":true}]},{"id":13,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"Which of the following sample sizes is appropriate for applying the Z test?","answers":[{"option":">30","bool":true},{"option":"25-30","bool":false},{"option":"<20","bool":false},{"option":"<25","bool":false},{"option":"10-15","bool":false}]},{"id":14,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A student has to present the association of liver cancer with five different socioeconomic and demographic variables along with their respective P-values and 95% confidence intervals. Which of the following data presentations would be most suitable for this scenario?","answers":[{"option":"Simple bar graph","bool":false},{"option":"Histogram","bool":false},{"option":"Table","bool":true},{"option":"Line graph","bool":false},{"option":"Pie chart","bool":false}]},{"id":15,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"You are asked to examine a female suspected of sexual assault. Examination findings reveal a deflorated female. Which of the following defines defloration?","answers":[{"option":"Virginity","bool":false},{"option":"Post coital bleed","bool":false},{"option":"Infertility","bool":false},{"option":"Rape","bool":false},{"option":"Loss of virginity","bool":true}]},{"id":16,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"You are asked to examine a female suspected of sexual assault. Examination findings reveal a ruptured hymen. What is the most common site of rupture of the hymen in a virgin female?","answers":[{"option":"Anterolateral","bool":false},{"option":"Posterolateral","bool":true},{"option":"Traumatic","bool":false},{"option":"Posterior","bool":false},{"option":"Anterior","bool":false}]},{"id":17,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"What is the type of sexual perversion in which the person gets sexual gratification by inflicting pain on their partner?","answers":[{"option":"Lesbianism","bool":false},{"option":"Saddism","bool":true},{"option":"Bestiality","bool":false},{"option":"Masochism","bool":false},{"option":"Sado-masochism","bool":false}]},{"id":18,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"Upon taking a detailed history from an offender, it is revealed that he frequently has intercourse with animals. What Is this sexual perversion termed?","answers":[{"option":"Bestiality","bool":true},{"option":"Saddism","bool":false},{"option":"Sodomy","bool":false},{"option":"Lesbianism","bool":false},{"option":"Masochism","bool":false}]},{"id":19,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"Which of the following statements about the anatomy of the kidneys is correct?","answers":[{"option":"Caliber of afferent arterioles is greater than the efferent arterioles","bool":false},{"option":"Cortical nephrons have lengthier loops of Henle than the juxtaglomerular nephrons","bool":false},{"option":"Vasa recta are not present in the renal pyramids","bool":false},{"option":"Medullary rays contain collection of renal corpuscles","bool":false},{"option":"Renal columns are the extensions of renal cortex between the adjacent renal pyramids","bool":true}]},{"id":20,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"Which of the following statements is correct about the development of the urinary system?","answers":[{"option":"Mesonephric tissue is responsible for the formation of permanent kidneys","bool":false},{"option":"Metanephric blastema is present at upper thoracic region","bool":false},{"option":"Loops of Henle develop from metanephric blastema","bool":true},{"option":"Ureteric buds develop into proximal convoluted tubules","bool":false},{"option":"Collecting ducts develop from metanephric blastema","bool":false}]},{"id":21,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"Every molecule of glucose gets reabsorbed in the proximal convoluted tubule. About 90% of the glucose that is filtered is reabsorbed in the initial segment of the proximal convoluted tubule. Which glucose transporter plays a key role in transporting the majority of glucose from the brush border epithelium into the cell, out of the tubular lumen?","answers":[{"option":"Na-Glucose co-transporter 2 (SGLT2)","bool":true},{"option":"GLUT1","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT2","bool":false},{"option":"GLUT4","bool":false},{"option":"Na-glucose cotransporter 1 (SGLT1)","bool":false}]},{"id":22,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"In which segment of the renal tubule are the sodium-hydrogen antiporters responsible for hydrogen ion secretion situated?","answers":[{"option":"Collecting duct","bool":false},{"option":"Distal convoluted tubule","bool":false},{"option":"Loop of Henle - thin segment","bool":false},{"option":"Loop of Henle - thick segment","bool":false},{"option":"Proximal convoluted tubule","bool":true}]},{"id":23,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"During a clinical interview, the doctor asked the patient “What were your feelings when you were talking about a fractured arm you mentioned that you were a physical trainer and could easily lift ten-kilogram weight ten times in a minute”. Asking about emotions and feelings attached to various symptoms and problems in an interview is an example of which of the following?","answers":[{"option":"Funneling","bool":false},{"option":"Active listening","bool":false},{"option":"Selective reflection","bool":true},{"option":"Empathy","bool":false},{"option":"Praphrasing","bool":false}]},{"id":24,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 3-year-old boy presents with fever, dysuria, oliguria, and intense pain in the abdomen. Physical examination shows a prominent suprapubic area which is dull on percussion. Urinalysis reveals red blood cells but no proteinuria. A diagnosis of hydronephrosis was made. What is the important morphological feature of hydronephrosis?","answers":[{"option":"Cortical scarring and shrinking caused by thickening and hyalinization of the vessel walls","bool":false},{"option":"Cortical tubulointerstitial damage with small contracted kidney","bool":false},{"option":"Enlarged kidneys with multiple cysts in the cortex and medulla","bool":false},{"option":"Dilatation of renal calyces and pelvis with atrophy of renal parenchyma","bool":true},{"option":"Patchy interstitial suppurative inflammation, intratubular aggregates of neutrophilic tubulitis, and tubular necrosis","bool":false}]},{"id":25,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"An 8-month-old infant was diagnosed with autosomal recessive polycystic kidney disease. Which one of the following other abnormalities can develop in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"Retinal dystrophy","bool":false},{"option":"Intracranial berry aneurysm","bool":false},{"option":"Polycystic liver disease","bool":false},{"option":"Pancreatic cysts","bool":false},{"option":"Congenital hepatic fibrosis","bool":true}]},{"id":26,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"Which of the following statements are false regarding the etiology and pathogenesis of pyelonephritis and urinary tract infection?","answers":[{"option":"It is more common in males","bool":true},{"option":"Caused by gram-negative bacilli","bool":false},{"option":"The most common causative agent is E. coli","bool":false},{"option":"It is more common in females","bool":false},{"option":"It can be caused by ascending infection from the bladder or through hematogenous dissemination","bool":false}]},{"id":27,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 45-year-old woman has angina pectoris, polyuria, and polydipsia for the past 5 years. On physical examination, she has a body mass index (BMI) of 32 kg/m². Laboratory studies show an HbA1C of 10%. Urinalysis shows macroalbuminuria, with no ketonuria. Which one of the following morphological changes can be attributed to the patient's proteinuria?","answers":[{"option":"Hyaline arteriosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Papillary necrosis","bool":false},{"option":"Glomerular basement membrane thickening","bool":true},{"option":"Nodular glomerulosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Tubular basement membrane thickening","bool":false}]},{"id":28,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A clinical study is performed on laboratory findings in subjects with renal diseases. Loss of physiologic function accompanies many diseases. Loss of which of the following renal functions is most likely to be identified by laboratory measurement of the urine-specific gravity following water deprivation?","answers":[{"option":"Reabsorption","bool":false},{"option":"Concentration","bool":true},{"option":"Filtration","bool":false},{"option":"Blood flow","bool":false},{"option":"Secretion","bool":false}]},{"id":29,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 5-year-old boy presents with generalized and periorbital edema. Further investigations show hypoalbuminemia, lipiduria, and 3.74 g proteinuria. Which of the following conditions is the most likely cause in this patient?","answers":[{"option":"IgA nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Rapidly progressive glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Focal segmental glomerulosclerosis","bool":false},{"option":"Minimal Change Disease","bool":true},{"option":"Amyloidosis","bool":false}]},{"id":30,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"Nephrotic syndrome is a clinical complex characterized by massive proteinuria of 3.5 gm or more of protein loss per 24 hours, hypoalbuminemia, generalized edema, hyperlipidemia, and lipiduria. Which of the following causes of nephrotic syndrome is steroid-responsive?","answers":[{"option":"FSGS","bool":false},{"option":"Minimal change nephrotic syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Finnish type of congenital NS","bool":false},{"option":"Rapidly progressive glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Membranous glomerulonephritis","bool":false}]},{"id":31,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 30-year-old man complains of puffiness around his eyes and swelling of his feet for 2 weeks. On examination, his blood pressure is 155/95 mm Hg. Urine microscopic examination reveals oval fat bodies. Which of the following conditions is he most likely to have?","answers":[{"option":"Nephrotic syndrome","bool":true},{"option":"Ascending pyelonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Obstructive uropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Nephritic syndrome","bool":false},{"option":"Renal infarction","bool":false}]},{"id":32,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"Tubulointerstitial nephritis is inflammation that affects the tubules and the tissue surrounding them called \"Interstitial tissue.\" The onset of tubulointerstitial nephritis may be acute (sudden) or chronic (gradual) and often results in kidney failure. Which of the following is the most common cause of acute tubulointerstitial nephritis?","answers":[{"option":"Heavy metal toxins","bool":false},{"option":"Urate nephropathy","bool":false},{"option":"Allergic drug reaction","bool":true},{"option":"Certain types of blood cancer","bool":false},{"option":"Damage from a drug (not an allergic reaction)","bool":false}]},{"id":33,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 32-year-old case of diabetes mellitus and using alcohol occasionally, presented with loose stools, watery in consistency for 3 days. He has around 10-12 of these episodes every day. On examination, he was dehydrated, with around 200 ml of urine output in 24 hours. Initial investigation showed an Hb of 14.8 mg/dL, TLC 11.2 x 10³/L, platelet count of 324x 10³/L, K⁺ 9.4 mEq/L, HCO₃⁻ 18, Urea: 94. Among the mentioned laboratory parameters which of the following is a highly indicative marker for hemodialysis?","answers":[{"option":"Urine output","bool":false},{"option":"Creatinine","bool":false},{"option":"Potassium","bool":true},{"option":"Urea","bool":false},{"option":"Bicarbonate","bool":false}]},{"id":34,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 24-year-old female presented with decreased urination and hematuria for 2 days. She has been unwell for the past 15 days with a severe sore throat and high-grade fever with chills. On examination, she has a blood pressure of 150/100 mmHg, pulse of 94/min, and temperature of 100°F. Systemic and general physical examinations were unremarkable. Which of the following urinary casts is most specific for her illness?","answers":[{"option":"Granular casts","bool":false},{"option":"Hyaline casts","bool":false},{"option":"Epithelial casts","bool":false},{"option":"White cell casts","bool":false},{"option":"Red cell casts","bool":true}]},{"id":35,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 50-year-old male is admitted to the medical ward with a history of abdominal distention and pedal edema. He is diagnosed as a case of chronic liver disease (cirrhosis). A complete blood count (CBC) shows a Hb of 10 mg/dL, WBC 3x10 mm³, platelet count 105x10 mm³, serum albumin 2.7mg/dl, prothrombin time 18 sec, (normal: 11-14 sec). Serum sodium is 122 mEq/L, serum K⁺ 3.6 mg/L, creatinine 1.1 mg/dl. What is the cause of hyponatremia in this patient according to history and physical examination?","answers":[{"option":"Hypotonic hypervolumic hyponatremia","bool":true},{"option":"Hypertonic hyponatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypotonic euvolumic hyponatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Pseudohyponatremia","bool":false},{"option":"Hypotonic hypovolemic hyponatremia","bool":false}]},{"id":36,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 60-year-old male known diabetic for 8 years, taking oral hypoglycemic drugs is admitted to the medical intensive care unit (ICU) with an altered level of consciousness. There is no history of fever. There are no signs of meningeal irritation. Investigation: complete blood count (CBC) 11 mg/dL, WBC 5X10⁹ mm³, platelet count of 162 x10⁹ mm³. Random blood sugar (RBS) of 590 mg/dL, creatinine 1.2 mg/dL, serum sodium 168mg/dL, and a serum potassium of 3.9 mg/dl. For treating this patient, which of the following should not be given at this time to correct metabolic and electrolyte problems?","answers":[{"option":"Half Strength Saline","bool":false},{"option":"Ringer Lactate","bool":false},{"option":"Hypertonic saline","bool":true},{"option":"Regular insulin","bool":false},{"option":"Normal saline","bool":false}]},{"id":37,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 55-year-old male patient with poorly controlled diabetes mellitus presented with high-grade fever with chills, loin pain & tenderness over kidneys. His ultrasound shows hydroureter and hydronephrosis on the right side. What is the most appropriate management?","answers":[{"option":"Surgical nephrectomy","bool":false},{"option":"Should be given I/V antibiotics empirically","bool":false},{"option":"Can be managed as outpatient on oral antibiotics","bool":false},{"option":"Should be admitted given I/V antibiotics and drainage by percutaneous nephrostomy","bool":true},{"option":"Should be given I/V fluids & cranberry juice","bool":false}]},{"id":38,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 25-year-old pregnant female is advised a urine analysis and urine culture at 12 weeks of gestation. Which one of the following is correct regarding asymptomatic bacteriuria?","answers":[{"option":"More than 10³ organisms/ml is regarded as significant","bool":false},{"option":"Normal urine culture does not exclude asymptomatic bacteriuria","bool":false},{"option":"More than 10⁵ organisms/ml is regarded as significant","bool":true},{"option":"Any number of organisms is regarded as significant","bool":false},{"option":"Up to 10 organisms/ml is considered diagnostic","bool":false}]},{"id":39,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 49-year-old male known diabetic, went for a follow-up renal check-up and reports an eGFR of 36ml/min/1.73 m². He was carrying his report from 4 months back, showing Urea: 78 mg/dL, serum creatinine 2.3 mg/dL, eGFR was 38 ml/min/1.73 m², and albumin: creatinine ratio was 300 mg/g. What will be the stage of his disease?","answers":[{"option":"Stage 3b chronic kidney disease","bool":true},{"option":"Stage 2 chronic kidney disease","bool":false},{"option":"Stage 3a chronic kidney disease","bool":false},{"option":"Stage 4 chronic kidney disease","bool":false},{"option":"Stage 5 chronic kidney disease","bool":false}]},{"id":40,"info":"3rd-year/renal/2023","question":"A 50-year-old male, a known case of diabetes mellitus and hypertension comes to the emergency department with complaints of decreased appetite, easy fatigability, and progressive shortness of breath for the last 4-5 months. On examination, blood pressure was 165/90 mm of Hg, pulse 85 beats/min, and respiratory rate 26/min. He appears pale, with periorbital puffiness and bilateral pedal edema present. Lab parameters show an Hb of 8.0 mg/dL, a normal TLC and platelet count, BUN was 60, and serum creatinine was 3.2 mg/dL. Potassium was also high. An 8-month-old report showed the same levels of deranged renal parameters. What will be the best possible diagnosis?","answers":[{"option":"Acute glomerulonephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Acute on chronic renal failure","bool":false},{"option":"Interstitial nephritis","bool":false},{"option":"Chronic renal failure","bool":true},{"option":"Acute tubular necrosis","bool":false}]}]
export default arr